Return to the Overlook.
Doctor Sleep is a horror, fantasy film directed by Mike Flanagan.
Still scarred by the trauma he endured as a child at the Overlook Hotel, Dan Torrance faces the ghosts of the past when he meets Abra, a
courageous teen who desperately needs his help -- and who possesses a powerful extrasensory ability called the "shine".
Danny Torrance, played by Ewan McGregor.
Rose the Hat, played by Rebecca Ferguson.
Abra Stone, played by Kyliegh Curran.
Billy Freeman, played by Cliff Curtis.
Crow Daddy, played by Zahn McClarnon.
Snakebite Andi, played by Emily Alyn Lind.
Doctor Sleep is a 2019 American supernatural horror film
written, directed, and edited by Mike Flanagan.
It is a film adaptation of the 2013 novel by Stephen King
and serves as a sequel to The Shining (1980).
The film stars Ewan McGregor as Dan Torrance, a man with psychic abilities and a drinking problem,
who struggles with childhood trauma caused by the horrors at the Overlook Hotel.
Rebecca Ferguson, Kyliegh Curran, and Cliff Curtis have supporting roles as new characters: Abra Stone
and Billy Freeman team up with Dan to take down Rose the Hat and her gang of followers.
Warner Bros.
Pictures began developing a film adaptation shortly
after Doctor Sleep was published in 2013.
Writer-producer Akiva Goldsman wrote a script, but the studio did not secure a budget for the film
until the box office success of its 2017 horror film It, also based on a novel by King.
Flanagan was hired to rewrite Goldsman's script
and direct the Doctor Sleep film.
Flanagan said he wanted to reconcile the differences
between The Shining novel and film.
Filming began in September 2018 in Georgia, including Atlanta and
the surrounding area, and concluded that December.
Doctor Sleep held its world premiere at the Regency Village Theater in Los Angeles on October 21, 2019, and was
theatrically released worldwide on October 31, 2019, and in the United States on November 8.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised Flanagan's direction and screenplay, and the
performances of the cast (especially McGregor, Ferguson, and Curran) but criticized its runtime.
Grossing $72.4 million worldwide, its performance at the box office was a disappointment compared
to the other King adaptations released in 2019: It Chapter Two and Pet Sematary.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
supernatural, haunted house, melancholy, sequel.
The tone is dark and intense.